MONTGOMERY FLAGG

(831) 236-3989 monteflagg@gmail.com Los Angeles, CA PORTFOLIO GITHUB LINKEDIN

ABOUT

After 12 years in customer experience and support and 8 years of experience co-founding and operating a mobile app development company, I decided to invest in myself and complete AppAcademy's rigorous Full Stack Engineer Program, elevating my technical knowledge and expertise to pursue a new career in Product. I am looking to join a company where I can leverage and develop my product management, user experience and/or programming skills while adding my creativity and acumen to the team.

EXPERIENCE

Volunteer Frontend Software Engineer

Reclaim Foundation - Online Trauma Support Community | Los Angeles, CA (Remote)

Nov. 2021 - Present

• Collaborate with a team of volunteer engineers in coordination with a ticketing system to receive work assignments, report progress and launch completed features on a MongoDB, Flask, Node, and React stack.

Co-Founder

Pheebo Inc. - Mobile App Development and Management Startup | Los Angeles, CA

Jan 2011 - Dec 2019

- Procured and managed seven mobile app and design contracts worth over \$500k in gross revenue in categories including a CRM platform, commerce, educational gaming, video entertainment, camera capture and more.
- Wore many hats with experiences as a Product Manager, Frontend Web Developer, User Experience Designer, Product
 Marketing Manager, Business Developer, & Technical Recruiter.
- Filed incorporation documents, negotiated equity splits and organized vesting schedules. Secured initial funding & managed finances as CFO for the first 3 years. Also, originated Pheebo's name, logo, and branding.

Customer Experience Manager & Product Expert

Compass Inc. | Los Angeles, CA

Dec. 2018 - Mar. 2021

- Oversaw and managed customer experience and product education for over 150 Real Estate professionals across Southern
 California assisting them to leverage industry-leading solutions, comprising of technology & software suites, financial
 programs and company specialists to help grow their businesses.
- Managed a team to strategize and design Monthly Product Newsletters sent to all 3000+ SoCal Agents to increase product education, prompt product adoption and help attain company Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).
- Helped lead the SoCal market to be #1 in the nation in Product Adoption in multiple categories for the year 2019 with an engineered, planned-out, multimedia action plan to increase Compass CRM adoption market-wide.

Customer Experience Specialist & Learning and Development Facilitator

Enjoy LLC. | Los Angeles, CA

Feb. 2016 - Dec. 2018

- Helped launch the Southern California market from inception including setting up the local warehouses, presenting at recruiting events across the market, and training new employees growing from 5 to 50+ team members and covering 80% of the metro Los Angeles and Orange Country areas.
- Designed and facilitated market and nation-wide workshops centered around company culture & values, product knowledge, HR benefits & requirements and new employee training for groups as large as 100.
- Delivered over 1000 product education experiences for customers attaining all metric goals while averaging 4.99 out of 5 stars for all customer reviews.

Customer Support Specialist & Product Development Associate

Hulu Inc. | Los Angeles, CA

Sept. 2011 - Aug. 2012

- Originator of *Huluminate* a cross-departmental think-tank system to share new ideas, improvements and suggestions across the organization.
- Provided customer support for product education, billing issues and technical troubleshooting, as well as filed and directed engineering bugs and improvements to appropriate departments and individuals, followed up with detailed testing.
- Implemented improvements to new hire training program, internal processes and user experiences on living room devices, mobile platforms and the Hulu web app.

PROJECTS

SHOULD I? (Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Social-media, polling web app that allows users to post poll questions with options and receive votes from other users.

- Implemented conditional React rendering to support both text and images as poll options so each could be visually represented and interacted with differently.
- Constructed a unidirectional data flow architecture with a single application-level state object to prevent mutated state and data collision, and to ensure reliable DOM rendering.
- Engineered a Flask and Redux one-click & one-route voting system that creates, changes and deletes a vote depending on the user's DOM selection.

STAYQUAINT (Javascript / Express / Sequelize / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Booking and reviewing web app for quaint, low-scale inns, cabins and bed and breakfasts inspired by Airbnb.

- Built modular React components and modals to allow for flexible expansion and added features.
- Implemented data schema with a new lodging form that creates four new instances in four different tables and renders those needed elements without refresh using Redux. .

TABLETALK (Python / Flask / SQLAlchemy / React / Redux / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Restaurant reservation and social meetup web app allowing users to reserve and share their table inspired by OpenTable.

- Engineered site to support two different user types, one for general users and one for businesses, with different account authentication, signup and different web experiences including a conditionally rendered Navbar.
- Comprehensive database schema with 11 data tables utilizing many-to-many, one-to-many and one-to-one relationships.

GOODTUNES (Javascript / Express / Sequelize / PUG / HTML / CSS / NodeJS)

live | github

Music discovery, managing and reviewing web app to help find your next best listen inspired by GoodReads.

- Connected PostgreSQL backend to the <u>Discogs API</u> to access a larger database of albums and information to increase application utility and experience.
- Implemented a search bar using an Express backend with the <u>Discogs API</u> to improve user experience by making all albums in the Discogs database accessible throughout the application

EDUCATION

Entrepreneur and Business Management Program - The Power MBA

- A complete business program and MBA alternative learning concepts, tools and methodologies from global business leaders such as founders and executives from Youtube, Netflix, Tesla, Airbnb, Whole Foods, Red Bull, Airbus, Shazam, & more.
- Coursework includes: Business Model innovation, Testing Business Ideas & The Lean Startup, Business & Marketing
 Strategies, Leadership, Entrepreneurship & Fundraising, Finance & Accounting, HR & Talent Management, and more.

Full-Stack Web Development - App Academy | Graduated Sept. 2021

- 24-week, 1000-hour immersive and intensive full-stack software engineer program with less than 3% acceptance rate.
- Coursework included: Object-Oriented Programming, REST, Systems Design, Coding Best Practices, Data Structures

BA Economics - *UCLA* | *Graduated Sept. 2015*

- Member of Anderson School of Management Entrepreneurship Association (Only Undergrad at UCLA admitted)
- Social Entrepreneurship Academy winner for Non-Profit Idea & Business Plan
- Member of Bruin Entrepreneurs Club
- Residential Advisor & Office Assistant for 2 years
- UCLA Radio Co-Marketing Director and DJ

Javascript, Python, React, Redux, Express, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Sequelize, PostgresSQL, HTML, PUG, Jinja, CSS, Git, Docker, Heroku, Node.js, Object Oriented Programming, REST API, Test Driven Development, UX/UI Mock-up and Design, Logo and Icon Design, Business Development, Product Management, Marketing Strategies, Training and Facilitation